Set, hut!
開始
Nice job, nice job. Tempo, tempo. Let's go.
很好 很好 速度 速度 上
Reset.
重來
Tempo, tempo. Let's pick it up this time, boys.
速度 速度 繼續戰鬥 孩子們
What personnel they got, Coach? All right, let's change it.
教練 他們什麼陣容？好的 我們換
Wall right, wall right.
右側 右側
Make sure you pick off the flyer. Here we go, here we go. Everybody up!
確保接住球 上 上 動起來
Ready. Set!
準備 預備
Set, hut!
預備 開始
There you go. Nice job. Nice job.
這邊 不錯 不錯
Mike did. Someone to help me with maximum protection. Mike did.
邁克拼盡全力保護我
Someone to help me call the play. Mike did.
邁克幫我訓練
Someone to help me get the team in line. Mike did it.
邁克幫我融入全隊
Mike controlled it, Mike ran it.
邁克掌控全域 邁克一直在做
We needed him, we used him,
我們需要他 不能沒有他
we leaned on him.
他是我們的依靠
He was our strength in our offense.
他是我們力量的源泉
I know this man. I know his backside as well as anybody.
我知道他 我比所有人都瞭解他
Simply, nothing has ever compared to Mike Webster.
坦白講 再好的形容詞用在邁克·韋伯斯特身上都不為過
Ladies and gentlemen, the greatest center in the history of the National Football League,
女士們先生們 將進入美國職業橄欖球聯盟名人堂歷史的人
your inductee into the Hall of Fame, number 52, "Iron Mike" Webster!
他身穿52號球衣"鐵人"邁克·韋伯斯特
震盪效應
I'd like to begin obviously,
顯然 我喜歡這個開局
I want it to be fun, but I want to be truthful.
我想試著幽默一點 但我更想真實點
Because the people out there are tremendous fans.
畢竟這兒還是有大量的球迷
Locally, but as we go through this,
但是當我們站在現場感受這一切
I want you to understand the greatest thing that has happened to me,
我希望你們能明白 對於我來說最棒的事情
in my experience in professional football,
是在我的橄欖球職業生涯裡
is to have the opportunity to work with people with a common goal.
是能夠有機會和有共同目標的人一起工作
And with the same purpose, and to sacrifice...
為了同樣的目標 不惜一切…
I'll tell you this, it's painful to play football, obviously.
我想說 打橄欖球顯然是不容易的
And it's not a lot of fun out there, to be in two-a-day drills
訓練並沒有什麼樂趣 夏天度日如年地操練
in the heat of summer, banging heads,it's not a natural thing.
頭頂著頭 這不正常
I was scared to fail, honest to god, I was scared I'd fail.
我害怕失敗 真的 我很害怕
I'm still scared of that.
到現在我都很怕
And all we have to do is finish the game.
而我們要做的就是結束比賽
If we finish, we win. Yeah
當比賽結束 我們贏了 就是這樣
基於真實故事
賓夕法尼亞州  匹茲堡
2002年 九月
The State has asked,
聯邦發問
after a lengthy trial, a death sentence,
經過漫長的審議 一次死刑判決
and two appeals, why we would learn anything new from you?
兩次上訴 我們為什麼要相信你會帶來新證據？
Dr.Omalu, Do you have a medical degree?
奧奧馬魯醫生 你有醫學學位嗎？
Yes, from the University of Nigeria.
是的 奈及利亞大學的
At Enugu, Nigeria.
在埃努古 奈及利亞
I did my residency at Columbia University Medical School in New York.
我居住在紐約的哥倫比亞大學醫學院
I also have masters degrees in public health and epidemiology.
我還有公共衛生和流行病的碩士學位
In addition, I am a certified physician executive,
同時 我還是個有執照的醫生
with a specialty in emergency medicine.
專長是急診醫學
And of course I'm board certified in
當然 委員會認證了我的
forensic pathology, clinical pathology and anatomic pathology.
法醫病理學 臨床病理學 還有解剖病理學
My focus is neuropathology, the examination of the brain.
我的中心工作是神經病理學 對大腦的研究
- While working as a... - I'm sorry, so sorry, I'm sorry.
- 當開始研究… - 抱歉 抱歉
I am also completing my MBA
我還在卡耐基馬林大學
at Carnegie Malin University.
完成了我的工商管理碩士學業
Oh, uh, and before I came to America, a Masters Degree
在我來美國之前 我還有
in the Theory of Music from the Royal School of Music in London.
倫敦皇家音樂學院音樂理論的碩士學位
But, oh, your original question, what I can add?
不過 你先問了 我還要補充什麼嗎？
My specialty is the science of death.
我的專業是死因調查
I think more about why people die than I do the way people live.
比起生活的意義 我更關注死亡的原因
Hands of the deceased.
死者的手
Broken and dislodged fingernails.
破碎和脫落的指甲
The hands of a woman, who fought wildly, for her life.
一個 曾為自己的生命 激烈反抗過的女人的手
And lost...
最終失去了…
The hands of the defendant, Thomas Chambers,
被告湯瑪斯·錢伯斯的手
and that is in fact the blood of the victim.
這實際上是受害者的血
Then doesn't that suggest that the state has the right man?
這不就證明政府抓對認了嗎？
I thought so, until I heard
我原以為是這樣 直到我聽到
Hour 217 of Mr Chamber's police interview.
員警對錢伯斯先生217小時的調查內容
I heard him very clearly say: "I hate blood".
我很清楚地聽見他說:"我討厭血"
I had a tooth pulled as a child once,
小時候我拔過一次牙
and it would not stop bleeding.
牙齦不停地出血
- So I got curious. - what about?
- 這樣我就覺得奇怪了 - 怎麼了？
Hands, I could not reconcile...
那些手 我不能理解…
these conflicting sets of hands. So my mind is going mad...
衝突的雙手 我覺得我快要瘋了…
So I'm trying to figure out...
所以我想弄清楚…
If Thomas Chambers' family has a history of hemophilia.
湯瑪斯·錢伯斯家族是不是有血友病的歷史
So I asked his father and his father said no.
所以我去問他的父親 但是他的父親說沒有
But, there is a strain of hemophilia, hemophilia A...
但是 有一種血友病 A型血友病…
It is so rare that it is never tested for...
它太罕見了所以從沒去檢測…
Mr. Chambers tested positive for hemophilia A...
錢伯斯先生的A型血友病檢測結果是陽性…
His hands may have touched the victim perhaps, to aid her as he claims,
他的手可能接觸過受害者 如他所說是要幫她
If his hands had been the murder weapon,
如果他用手去殺人
if he had been scratched or bitten,
如果他被抓了或咬到了
he would have bled to death.
他會流血而死
If the state of Pennsylvania, moves forward to execute,
如果賓夕法尼亞州法院執行了死刑判決
You would be killing an innocent man.
你們將會殺死一個無辜的人
- Happy Birthday to... - Way to go Joe.
- 生日快樂… - 喬 走開
- Good morning, Gracie. - Good morning, Dr.Omalu.
- 早上好 翠西 - 早上好 奧奧馬魯醫生
- Here are the cases for today. - This is from yesterday.
- 這是今天的記錄 - 這是昨天的
Hey, I got a full room today, cycle them through.
嘿 整間房子都滿了 開始檢查吧
Yes sir.
嗯
Let's begin with Rachel Greene.
從瑞秋·格林開始吧
Okay Rachel, I need your help.
瑞秋 我需要你的説明
We are in this together.
現在我們是一起的
Please help me to find out what happened to you.
請幫我找出發生在你身上的事
- Here we go... - Danny, come on.
- 一起來吧… - 丹尼 拜託
Gracie...
翠西…
Dr.Omalu uses different stuff, makes less of a mess.
奧奧馬魯醫生使用不同的工具 減少交叉感染
Possible cause of relationship between...
可能是它們之間的關係惡化了
self-medication and early head trauma.
自行用藥和早期頭部創傷
Leading to narcotics abuse and overdo
導致了藥物的濫用
You're not her shrink, Bennet.
你不是精神病學家 班尼特
If I know how she lived, I know why she died.
如果我知道她的生活狀況 我就知道她的死因了
And you should be careful, Danny.
你應該小心點的 丹尼
One day I may be rushing through your autopsy.
說不定哪天我會解剖你的屍體
Dr.Wecht, Dr.Omalu is here to see you.
威切特醫生 奧奧馬魯醫生來見你
You know the reason why you're not back in Nigeria, don't you?
你知道你不回尼日尼亞去的原因嗎？
Yes, because I remind you of you.
知道 因為我提醒過你
Only less handsome. Sit.
別耍帥了 坐吧
- What the hell is going on down there? - Nothing, I'm doing my work, I'm fine.
- 到底是怎麼回事？- 沒事 我在做我的工作 我很好啊
You're not fine, Danny hates your guts, I've never seen anything like it.
騙誰呢 丹尼討厭你的衝動 我從來沒有見過他像這樣
I think you're working a little too slow.
我我覺得你工作有點慢了
I'm a doctor, the dead are my patients.
我是一個醫生 死者是我的病人
I treat them with respect.
我尊重他們
But do you have to talk to them?
這就是你和他們談話的原因嗎？
If you have to do that, talk to them in your head.
如果必須談話 心中默念就好
And we discussed the knives, you're still throwing them away.
我們談談手術刀吧 你還在丟棄手術刀
We're a public agency in Pittsburgh, they're expensive.
我們是匹茲堡的公共醫院 手術刀很貴的
Reuse them.
要重複利用
Would you want me, to cut open your mother
你同意我拿用在連環殺手身上的手術刀
with the same knife I used on a serial killer?
給你的母親開刀嗎？
Yes, I'd probably request it.
同意 我求你了
You need a girlfriend,
你該找個對象了
You need to touch somebody alive once in a while occasionally.
你需要多和活人接觸
Living women, well occasionally they're a pain in the ass,
活的女人 雖然偶爾她們會很煩人
but quite often they're amazing.
但更多的時候是比較有意思的
Give it a try.
試試吧
Okay.
好吧
Just be, a little less of an artist, fit in a little more.
別那麼特立獨行 融入周圍
Yes.
嗯
It's another death row case, the guy's being railroaded.
這又是一個死刑案 這傢伙被陷害入獄了
A thousand dollars for you.
這1000美元是你的了
Cyril...
西瑞爾…
Webby. Hey, man.
嗨 夥計
I am loving the digs.
我喜歡這住處
Mike? It's Justin.
邁克？我是賈斯汀
If I just sit with you a minute, huh?
我能和你一起坐一會兒嗎？
Joker.
你這傢伙
We're all worried about you, man.
我們都很擔心你 夥計
What are you doing, Mike? Mike.
你要幹嘛？邁克 邁克
- Don't do it - It's alright...
- 別這樣 - 沒事的…
I just, I don't wanna go to sleep.
我只是 我不想入睡
I heard you sold your Super Bowl rings, Mike.
我聽說你把自己的超級碗戒指賣了 邁克
Your Super Bowl rings, Mike
超級碗的戒指啊 邁克
Mike, hey, Pam's your wife.
邁克 嘿 帕姆是你的妻子
- Garrett's your boy. - Yeah.
- 加勒特是你的兒子 - 嗯
I'm starting to forget things.
我開始忘記事情
I'm saying this crazy crap to my kids.
我還對我的孩子們瘋言瘋語
I nearly pushed Keana into a wall.
我幾乎把基娜推到牆裡面
- I never thought I'd do that to her. - Well, don't... just don't give up.
- 我從沒想過我會那麼對她 - 不要… 不要放棄自己
All we gotta do...
我們所要做的…
is finish the game. And we'll all be winners.
是結束比賽 那麼我們就是贏家
Have a good day, it's good to see you
開心點 見到你很高興
- Oh, Bennet, a moment. - Yes, father?
- 班尼特 等一下 - 怎麼了 神父？
- How are you. - We have a new member, a young lady from Kenya.
- 你好 - 我們有一個新朋友 一個來自肯亞的年輕女士
She came to us a couple of weeks ago and she needs our help.
她幾周前剛過來 她需要我們的説明
Sure, how much do you need, Father?
明白 你需要多少錢 神父？
She needs shelter, Bennet, until we find her something permanent.
她需要住所 班尼特 直到她有工作穩定下來
Father, my... I... I'm working on my MBA, I'm studying... my books are all over everywhere.
神父 我… 我正在讀工商管理碩士 我忙著讀書 我的書扔的到處都是
She's a nice girl, she's from Nairobi.
她是個很不錯的女孩 從奈洛比過來的
Went to a British school, she wants to work.
在英國上的學 她想找個工作
We're letting her tidy around the church.
我們讓她打掃教堂
We're asking you because
我們請你幫忙 是因為
we know she'll be safe and cared for.
我們知道她會安全且被照顧地很好
- I feel God in you, Bennet. - Thank you, father.
- 我知道你很善良 班尼特 - 謝謝 神父
Where is she?
她在哪？
So... you can see.
呃… 如你所見
That is basically my office there.
這基本上是我的辦公室
Is that your father?
那是你父親嗎？
Ah yes, The Chief.
是的 還是個酋長
Those are my peaches.
這是我的桃子
They should not be here.
不該在這的
Your room, there is a...
你的房間 有…
the key for you.
給你的鑰匙
How are you for money? I have something...
你有錢嗎？我有一些…
Need is not weak.
需求不代表軟弱
Need is need.
需求就是需求
I know where you are, I was you.
我知道你的情況 我曾跟你一樣
You are in America now, so,
你現在是在美國 所以
you have to be the best version of yourself.
你必須做最好的自己
If you don't know what that is, you pick something and fake it.
如果你不知道那是什麼 你就選一個並裝成那個樣子
I will put it there for you.
我替你把它放這兒
- What did you pick? - What did I pick?
- 你選的什麼？- 我選擇什麼？
- To fake. - I picked an older, bald headed white man.
- 偽裝 - 我選了一個又老又禿的白人
Why an older, bald headed white man?
為什麼是個又老又禿的白人？
Because he is the best at what he does.
因為他是他所從事的領域裡最傑出的人
Do you want to see your room?
你想看看你的房間嗎？
I was a registered nurse.
我是一個有執照的護士
At the Aogakan hospital in Nairobi.
我曾在奈洛比的奧嘎刊醫院工作過
I understand, I meant no offense.
明白 無意冒犯
Hey, hey , wake up. Hey.
嘿 醒醒
Wake up, you.
醒醒 叫你呢
Come on now, this ain't no hotel, you can't sleep here.
快點 這可不是酒店 你不能在這兒睡
Put down your window, let's go.
車窗放下來 走開
You're Mike Webster, right? Iron Mike.
你是邁克·韋伯斯特？真的嗎？鐵人邁克
- I called for him, he's coming. - Okay, well, I don't see him.
- 我打電話給他了 他就來 - 好吧 我沒有看到他
Oh, come on, Claude.
哦 拜託 克勞德
Come on, come on.
拜託 拜託
Mike, he's here.
邁克 他在這兒
- Hey, Mike. - Look you, uh...
- 嗨 邁克 - 看看你…
- Mike, can you hear me? - Oh, yeah, yeah. I just uh...
- 邁克 你能聽到我說話嗎？- 能 我只是…
You just, uh, you just have to tell me to do, because I am...
你只要 呃 你只需要告訴我該怎麼做 因為我…
I am freaking overwhelmed.
我不知道該幹嘛
- We're gonna get you some help, Mike. - What are you taking right now?
- 我們會給你一些幫助邁克 - 你現在在做什麼？
- The Ritalin. - Dexedrine, Prozac still takin all of those?
- 利他林 - 中樞神經刺激劑 百憂解 扭角羚都要嗎？
- Sit down. - Yeah, all of it, and super glue.
- 坐吧 - 是的 全部都要 還有強力膠
- Okay Mike - 3.5 Haldol, you call his wife,
- 好的邁克 - 3.5的氟呱啶醇 給他妻子打電話
You tell her he is worse, he's a lot worse.
你告訴她 他現在很糟糕 非常糟糕
You were my doctor , You were my doctor, right?
你是我的醫生 你是我的醫生 對吧？
- I was the team doctor I was everybody's... - Okay, the Team doctor.
- 我是隊醫 我是每個人的… - 好的 是隊醫
Okay, alright then, the Team doctor. Then why aren't you helping me alright?
好吧好吧 隊醫 那你為什麼不把我治好啊？
- I am going to help you... - You are not helping me...
- 我會幫助你的… - 你沒有…
- You gotta fix this, you gotta fix this, alright? - Doctor?
- 你必須解決這裡的問題 你要解決這個問題 - 醫生嗎？
In here, Alright ?
這裡的問題 知道嗎？
And in here, I am dying in here.
還有這 非常難受
- I'm dying in here alright. - I'll take care of you, Mike.
- 難受死了 - 我會照顧你的 邁克
It's okay.
好了
Let me give you something to help you rest, Mike.
讓我先幫助你休息一會 邁克
You want to rest, don't you?
你想要休息 是吧？
I just want you to help me alright , I just want you to help me.
我只是想讓你幫幫我 我只是想讓你幫幫我
- I'll help you, Mike. - Just help me.
- 我會幫你的 邁克 - 幫幫我
Come and sit down.
過來坐下
Well, go ahead, give me the drugs, give me the drugs
好吧 隨便了 打針吧 來點藥
- Show me how you're going to help me... - Don't move, Mike.
- 讓我看看你怎麼幫我… - 不要動 邁克
Come and sit down, Mike.
過來坐下 邁克
Come lay down, Mike.
來 躺下 邁克
You rest now. Mike.
現在開始休息 邁克
- What am I missing? - A tumor?
- 我漏掉了什麼嗎？- 腫瘤？
No, all of his scans were clean.
不是 所有的掃描結果都是正常的
Over the years, the dauntless Webster had abandoned his family,
多年來 不屈不撓的韋伯斯特 已經放棄了他的家庭
slipped into financial chaos, and homelessness.
陷入經濟危機 無家可歸
This is a hard day for the city of Pittsburgh.
對匹茲堡來說這是艱難的一天
On a personal note, I can remember sitting down with my father,
在我的私人日記裡 我還記著 他和我父親坐在一起
and him giving me examples of hard work ethic.
並且他給我舉了工作模範的例子
And telling me when you get knocked down, you get back up again...
他告訴我 當你被撞倒了 你再爬起來…
Sorry, I don't usually watch TV.
抱歉 我很少看電視
Then why do you have one?
那你為什麼有電視？
One has a TV in this country.
這個國家每個人都有電視
Oh, I'm Sorry, I don't usually eat breakfast.
哦 對不起 我通常不吃早餐
One should eat breakfast in this country.
在這個國家每個人都應該吃早餐
Dear God, thank you for the gifts. you have so graciously bestowed upon us.
親愛的上帝 謝謝您的饋贈 如此慷慨地給予我們
Please help us to continue to be deservant of your blessings.
請讓我們能一直得到您的庇佑和祝福
Amen.
阿門
Bennet
班尼特
Just hours after he was rushed to a nearby hospital,
在他被送往醫院的幾個小時後
Recall Hall of Famer, "Iron" Mike Webster...
撤銷名人堂成員"鐵人"邁克·韋伯斯特…
- What is going on? - Mike Webster.
- 這到底是怎麼回事 - 邁克·韋伯斯特
Who's Mike Webster?
誰是邁克·韋伯斯特？
He's the greatest centre to ever play the game, he's a true warrior.
他是歷史上最偉大的中鋒 他是一個真正的勇士
- I'm sorry, what is a "centre"? - The big guy in the middle, hikes it.
- 對不起"中鋒"是什麼？- 中間的大個子
- My kid plays football because of this guy. - Okay. I'm sorry, I just did not know who he was.
- 我的孩子打橄欖球就是因為這傢伙 - 好吧 我很抱歉 我不知道他是誰
Well, if you're going to live in this town, you're going to work in this town, football is a good thing.
如果你要在這個城市生活 你要在這個城市工作 橄欖球是一個好東西
I freaking can't believe it's you.
我真不敢相信是你
Look, as you know I was put on the schedule for this weekend.
你知道我這個週末的排程
I am put on the schedule for every weekend.
我每個週末都有安排
Come on, come on.
拜託 拜託
The whole town was out of work.
整個城市都停下來了
He was the guy that gave us hope when there really was no hope.
在沒有希望的時候這個傢伙給了我們希望
Just... leave him be.
只是… 他離開了
Look at his teeth.
看他的牙齒
He was pulling them out and supergluing them back in
他把它們拉出又用強力膠黏回去
Gracie, full autopsy, please.
翠西 完整解剖
Hey, come on, man, there's no need to cut this man's body.
噢 拜託 夥計 沒必要切開他的身體吧
Why does an apparently healthy, favourite son of this city....
為什麼一個健康的 這個城市最受歡飲的人…
Become self mutilating and homeless at 50?
在50歲時開始虐待自己並且無家可歸？
Cardiac arrest may be how he died but not why.
心臟停止跳動讓他死亡了 當那並不是死亡的原因
Prepare the body, please.
清潔遺體
I think what he's saying is that...
我想他的意思是…
Sometimes in life, you know you just...
有時候在生活中 你知道你…
You're asked to leave it alone.
你想要隨它去吧
But sometimes you can't.
但是有時候你不能
Do you think he believes it is a time I should leave it alone?
你覺得他認為這是個小事 我應該不管它嗎？
No, I don't.
不 沒有
I never leave it alone, that's why people hate me.
我從不隨波逐流 那就是人們討厭我的原因
Mike... people are saying bad things about you.
邁克… 人們都在說你的壞話
I can tell something is wrong.
我想說有些事情是錯的
But I can't do this alone.
但是我自己一個人做不到
I need your help, to tell the world what happened to you.
我需要你的説明 告訴這個世界你身上發生了什麼
Uh, sorry...
哦 抱歉
Regular folds of gray matter, no obvious contusions.
腦灰質褶皺正常 沒有明顯的挫傷
No shrinkage from Alzheimers.
沒有老年癡呆萎縮症狀
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Can you show me the CT scan again please?
能把CT掃描件再給我看一下嗎？
- How old are these? - Six months.
- 這些東西多久了？- 六個月前的
Six months, okay.
六個月 行了
His brain should be a mess, but...
他的大腦應該很糟糕 但是…
It looks completely normal.
它看上去很正常
Records say: severe headaches,
記錄中有:嚴重的頭痛
double vision, voices...
頭部會產生…
in his head.
重影和重音
No documented concussions.
沒有腦震盪記錄
He did complain of dizziness.
他總是抱怨頭暈
- Yes, How often? - Once.
- 噢 經常抱怨嗎？- 是的
In 18 years of professional football?
18年的橄欖球職業生涯嗎？
Joseph Maroon.
約瑟夫·馬路恩
Sign the certificate, sew him up.
在證明上簽字 縫合
Fix the brain, please.
固定大腦
You know we don't have the budget to do that.
你知道我們沒有那麼多的預算
People do not go mad for no reason, I'm going to continue looking.
人不會無緣無故發瘋 我要找到原因
- No, you're not going to. - Danny, you are out of line.
- 不可能 - 丹尼你過分了
- Hey, you do not speak to me like that. - I am the pathologist on duty.
- 嘿 不要這樣對我說話 - 我是值班的病理學家
- I am the pathologist on record. - Listen This is not your laboratory.
- 病理記錄上簽的我名字 - 聽好了 這不是你自己的實驗室
My hands are on this body If I am wrong, I am wrong.
我給這遺體做的檢查 如果我做錯了 那是我的錯誤
- And you are wrong - Not you, me
- 你就是錯了 - 不是你說了算 是我
- Fix that brain. - Hey, I am going to make sure that they don't pay for any of this.
- 固定大腦 - 我要確保他們不為做這件事超支
I am going to write my orders for the tests that I need.
我會寫我要做的測試的清單
- Then you're paying for it yourself. - Yes, Danny.
- 那你自己付錢去 - 可以
Please, exit my workplace.
請你離開我的工作室
Please.
走開
In 25 years I've never requested a panel of tests like this.
25年來我從未如此要求過檢測小組
What are you looking for?
你想要幹什麼？
There is not a single case, in a book or in life,
在書裡或者生活裡 從沒有發生過這樣的事情
where a man that healthy, went that mad, that young,
哪裡有一個健康年輕的男人像那樣瘋
with no visible abnormality of the brain.
而且大腦看起來很正常
- I don't know what I am looking for. - I can tell.
- 我不知道我在尋找什麼 - 我可以告訴你
- It's going to cost you a fortune. - I understand.
- 它會花費你一大筆錢的 - 明白
Okay, well, if you have to play hero, just make sure we both come out okay.
好吧 你要想成為英雄 但你得確保我們都不會有麻煩
Dr.Omalu, you got something today. I left it on your desk.
奧奧馬魯醫生 幫你收了一些東西 我放你桌子上了
Thank you.
謝謝
Prema...
普雷瑪
It's very late. Where have you been?
這麼晚 你去哪了？
I got a job.
我找到了一份工作
- Look at you... - Well, a shift.
- 你行的… - 嗯 一次轉變
At a home, feeding old people.
在別人家裡 照顧老年人
That is fantastic, congratulations.
太好了 恭喜你
What is that?
那是？
Mike Webster.
邁克·韋伯斯特
Raise is worth a thousand dollars and here we go...
讓我們從現在開始去賺夠1000美元吧…
Would you like me to get you a TV for your room?
要不要我買個電視放你臥室裡？
No, this one will be fine.
不用了 一個就好了
Oh, okay.
呃 好吧
I can't tell what you're more afraid of.
我不知道你在擔心什麼
What you will find...
你會找到什麼…
or what you won't
或者找不到什麼
Oh, My God.
哦 我的天呐
哦 天呐
Let's get the Jacked Up No. 5
讓我們一起為5號加油
Bringing it again with the Rams vs Chargers, Mark Bulger gonna be delivering the ball to Tony Fisher.
公羊隊和閃電隊再次狹路相逢 馬克·布傑要傳球給托尼·費舍爾
throws it down around his feet,
球扔到他的腳下了
So Donny Edwards is gonna level him right there.
丹尼·愛德華準備開始沖線了
Always be looking out for the big hit right there.
看來大個子總能在合適的時候發起衝擊
Tony Fisher got Jacked Up.
托尼·費舍爾受傷了
No.4, the Seahawks and the Chiefs, DJ Hackett.
4號 海鷹隊首領 DJ·哈科特
If you gonna make the catch in time, lord gotta watch your back...
如果你想趕時間 請先看看你的身後…
Eyes on me, Eyes on me
看我 看著我
Gentlemen...
先生們…
This is a game of awareness. It is a game of desire.
這是需要思維遊戲 這是需要欲望的遊戲
That's why we have the three whistle drill.
這就是為什麼場上有三個裁判的原因
Let's Go
動起來
When I blow this whistle three times...
當你聽到三次哨聲…
You seek out a team mate, any team mate
去尋找你的隊友 任何一個隊友
You make collision, You be physical, You be violent
像野獸一樣 去衝擊 去碰撞 暴力點
Bring it in here, let's go
就是現在 躁起來
The only way you're going to get this players hands off of you, You grab him by his throat and you squeeze.
你想讓這個運動員放手的辦法只有一個 你要用盡全力去扼住他們的喉嚨
You choke him until shit runs down his leg.
緊緊扼住直到他大小便失禁
Do you understand me?
聽明白了嗎？
Drive, drive, get up.
沖 沖 沖起來
Hit, drive, drive.
撞他 沖 沖
Jack wires in the Eagles, Dirk Johnson, and I'm gonna wait for this,
老鷹隊的傑克·維爾斯 德科·詹森 我一直在期待這一刻
Because the look on his face tells you that he got...
因為他臉上的表情在告訴你他…
Jacked up.
受傷了
And our No.1 hit of the week Jon Kitna dropping back to pass
我們的1號幹翻了喬恩·科塔回到了替補區
and Shawn Spencer and lifts him off his feet.
肖恩·斯賓塞完成了對他的擒抱
Oh, my God. And Jon Kitna got: Jacked Up.
噢 天啊 喬恩·科塔傷了
You should see this, Bennet.
你該看看這個 班尼特
It's actually, really beautiful.
很好看 真的很精彩
Yes he's got him touchdown.
他真的做到了 觸底得分
A tremendous catch.
一次關鍵的防守
Can I show you something?
我能給你看一些東西嗎？
The human brain resides in a fluid...
這裡邊泡著人的腦體樣本…
completely disconnected from the human brain.
完全脫離人的大腦
Bennet, will you relax? I can hear you breathing.
放鬆點 班尼特 我都能聽到你的呼吸聲
This is a really terrible brain.
這是一個有問題的大腦
Ever met the Great DeKosky before? Expect two minutes, tops.
之前從沒見過德庫思老師嗎？稍等兩分鐘
Is that him?
是他嗎？
So you're our prize graduate.
你就是那個優秀畢業生了
Tell him.
告訴他吧
- It's Mike Webster, the... - I know who Mike Webster is.
- 邁克·韋伯斯特 他是… - 我知道他是誰
Steve, he was 50.
史蒂夫 他才五十歲
You have my attention.
你提起我的興致了
The Cape Gannet, a diving bird,
塘鵝 一種水鳥
capable of generating speeds of up to
飛行速度非常快
75 mph.
能達到75公里每小時
Turning itself into a missile as it collides with the face of the sea.
沖向大海的時候變得像顆導彈一樣
The Red Head Woodpecker can absorb a G-force of one thousand,
這種紅色的啄木鳥能夠吸收1000G的重力加速度
pecking a tree 12 thousand times per day.
每天可以啄擊樹幹一萬兩千次
85 million times over it's lifetime.
一輩子要啄擊8500萬次
Big horned sheep can generate...
大角羊可以產生…
Bennet...
班尼特…
Okay, Okay.
好吧 好吧
All of these animals have shock absorbers.
這些動物都有自己的緩衝器
built into their bodies.
在它們體內
The woodpeckers tongue
啄木鳥的舌頭
extends through the back of the mouth out of the nostril
從嘴裡一直延伸到鼻部
encircling the entire cranium.
然後環繞了整個頭蓋骨
It is the anatomical equivalent
這是解剖可以看到的
of a safety belt for it's brain.
成了大腦的安全帶
Human beings, not a single piece of our anatomy
而人類 沒有一次解剖能證明
protects us from those types of collisions.
人體記憶體在腦震盪保護器
A human being will get concussed at 60 G's.
人體在60倍重力加速度的衝擊力下是會產生腦震盪的
A common head to head contact on a football field?
橄欖球比賽裡一次普通的頭碰頭的衝擊力有多大？
100 G's.
100倍重力加速度
God did not intend for us to play football.
上帝並沒有給我們打橄欖球的天賦
Let's keep God out of this.
別跟我們提上帝
Okay.
好吧
- What are S's? - The Steelers.
- 一串S是什麼意思？- 匹茲堡鋼人隊
- And the O's? - The "others", obviously.
- 那一串O又是什麼？- 顯然是別的隊
Yes, the other team.
嗯 別的隊伍
- Do you even watch football? - No, not at all.
- 你看過橄欖球比賽嗎？- 從來沒有
But I've been studying Mike Webster's position.
但是我深入瞭解了邁克·韋伯斯特的位置
The man in the middle, is quite deceptively the most violent position on the field.
他是個中鋒 這是球場上暴力衝擊最多的位置
The slaps, the punches, the forearm, it is a unremitting storm of sub-concussive blows.
推搡 衝撞 肘擊 他無時無刻不承受著這些持續性的打擊
The head as a weapon on every single play
甚至頭也成了每一個運動員的武器
of every single game, with every single practice, from the time he was a little boy...
每一場比賽 每一次練習 從他小時候開始…
to a college man, culminating in an 18-year professional career.
成為職業球員 18年的職業生涯
By my calculations, Mike Webster sustained
通過我的計算 我認為邁克·韋伯斯特
more than 70,000 blows to his head.
遭受了超過七萬次的腦部衝擊
Now, these men...
現在 這些人…
these are the fastest.
這些速度最快的人
Now their speed, multiplied by the speed of the men who hit them,
正在用它們各自速度衝擊著別人和自己的身體
The G Forces generated equivalent to hitting them on the head with a sledgehammer.
在它們頭部最終產生的重力加速度就像用大錘在敲打一樣
All of this triggered a cascading series of neurological events,
這些因素放在一起引發了一系列的神經問題
which unleashed killer proteins upon Mike Webster's brain.
邁克·韋伯斯特的大腦釋放的蛋白質成了殺手
The Tangles invading and strangling his mind,
它們糾纏在一起 影響他的意識
from the inside out.
從內到外
Like pouring wet concrete down kitchen pipes.
就像廚房下水道裡被灌注了混凝土
As it hardens, it chokes the brain,
當它凝固的時候 它卡住了大腦
leaving him unrecognizable.
讓他記不住事情
Even to himself
甚至是他自己
I don't know football, I've ever played.
我不瞭解橄欖球 我也沒玩過
But I am telling you
但是我現在告訴你
That playing football killed Mike Webster.
正是橄欖球生涯害死了了邁克·韋伯斯特
And I am certain there are others.
同時我敢肯定還會有其他人
And how can you possibly know that?
你是怎麼知道的？
Common sense, but they are either dead or lost in the way Mike Webster was lost.
常識 他們要麼會死掉 要麼就是像邁克·韋伯斯特那樣迷失下去
I'm not interested in common sense.
我對常識不感興趣
I'm interested in science.
我需要的是科學
And science is knowing.
科學才是真理
I know from these players records,
我從這些球員記錄得知
that their doctors believe that they have early Alzheimer's,
醫生診斷他們是早期阿爾茨海默氏症
which is statistically impossible...
從統計學來說是不可能的…
they are too young.
他們太年輕
Because it is not Alzheimer's, it is this.
因為它不是阿爾茨海默氏症 所以是碰撞造成的
I don't like it...
我不喜歡這個…
No, actually I hate it.
不 其實我討厭這件事
But as a scientist...
但是作為一個科學家…
I can't deny it.
我不能睜著眼說瞎話
Name it. You have to give this a name.
它叫什麼 你必須給它取個名字
I'm sorry. Did I wake you?
抱歉 打擾到你了嗎？
Did they agree? What it is?
他們同意了嗎？結果怎麼樣？
Yes, we are going to publish.
同意了 我們將要公佈了
They? with you?
他們和你一起？
Yes, in a medical journal.
是的 在一個醫學期刊上
- With you? - Yes, with me, together.
- 和你一起？- 是的 和我一起
That's so...
那麼…
- Congratulations. - Thank you, thank you.
- 恭喜你 - 謝謝 謝謝
- You... Are you going somewhere? - Yes, with you.
- 你… 你要出去嗎？- 是的 和你
To celebrate.
去慶祝
You don't dance, do you?
你不跳舞嗎？
I had quite a revelation tonight.
我今晚有點興奮
This body was made for dancing.
這身體就是為跳舞而存在的
When they say "dancing machine", I am what they mean.
他們說的"跳舞機器" 就是在說我呀
I am very proud of you.
我為你感到驕傲
Okay.
嗯
May I kiss you?
我可以吻你嗎？
- Good Morning - Cyril.
- 早啊 - 西瑞爾
It's very weird to bring women into the morgue at night.
大晚上的把妹子帶進太平間真是非常詭異啊
- She is a friend. - You don't have friends.
- 她是個朋友 - 你哪有朋友
Listen, Danny knows she's been in there.
聽著 丹尼知道她去過
He's thinking about filing a formal complaint.
他準備投訴你了
What? I was working on Webster.
什麼？我是在工作
I know, I'll take care of it.
我知道 我會解決的
How much has that cost you so far?
你到現在總共花費了多少錢？
- 20,000. - 20?
- 兩萬 - 兩萬？
I Save, everything.
我自己承擔
Really? How unamerican.
真的？非主流啊
Well, maybe it was worth it. I got the call.
也許你是對的 我接到了一個電話
"Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy" got a nice ring to it, doesn't it...
"慢性創傷腦部病變"聽起來不錯嘛 是吧…
Yes, CTE
是的 簡稱CTE
So what happens now?
那麼到底發生了什麼？
We publish, DeKosky is going to co-author.
我們發佈出來了 德庫思也是合著者
- DeKosky? - Yes, Omalu DeKosky.
- 德庫思？- 是的 奧奧馬魯 德庫思
And Cyril Wecht.
還有西瑞爾·威切特
- Well I'm very proud of you. - Thank you.
- 好吧 為你感到驕傲 - 謝謝
See? The gray is the right colour.
看到了嗎？灰色才是最好的顏色
The Blue shows dirt even in the rain.
在雨天裡藍色顯得很容易髒
Let's go, baby.
開始吧 夥計們
Going across...
穿過去了…
Arrgh
啊
- I'm hearing voices - Are you serious?
- 我聽到有聲音 - 不要緊吧？
Justin, stop, you're scaring them.
賈斯汀 停下來 你嚇到我了
Look at me
看著我
They're telling me to kill you. They're telling me to kill you.
他們要我殺了你 殺了你
Get out...
滾出去…
Don't. Why, God? No...
別 上帝啊 不…
All units... black pickup spotted...
所有單位請注意… 黑色皮卡…
I see him, just passing me.
我看見了 剛剛超過我
Reportedly driving into opposite traffic the last 10 miles...
我繞到路口過去需要10英里…
Oh, my God...
我的天啊…
Pickup has collided.
皮卡車爆炸了
All units... report
所有單位… 上報
A few months after Steeler favourite Justin Strzelczyk was killed in that fiery accident,
在鋼人隊最受歡迎的賈斯汀·斯托克斯死於一場交通事故的幾個月後
Yet another Steelers favourite Terry Long, has apparently committed suicide
另一個鋼人隊最受歡迎的球員特裡·隆 也被發現自殺身亡
at the age of 45.
今年45歲
Well, Terry, You wondered where they are now, now we know.
好吧 特裡 你想知道他們在哪裡 現在我們知道了
Terry Long, Pittsburgh Steelers.
特裡·隆 匹茲堡鋼人隊隊員
I guess these guys only die when you're working.
我覺得這些傢伙只在你工作的時候死去
What other problems did he have?
他有什麼其他的問題？
Arrested a few times, fraud, federal theft.
被逮捕過幾次 欺詐 盜竊
Wow, arrested a lot.
噢 多次被捕
I need a full autopsy, same tests as Mike Webster.
我需要做完整的解剖 像邁克·韋伯斯特那樣的
- You paying for that too? - Yes, Danny, I'm paying for that too.
- 你自己支付費用嗎？- 是的 丹尼 我支付
Joseph Maroon.
約瑟夫·馬路恩
This is my dream.
這是我的理想
The schools are good.
這些學校很好
You are good, Prema.
你也很好 普蕾瑪
I'm sure you see good in me.
我相信你也能看到我的好
I see all that you are.
我懂
I want to marry you.
我想要娶你
We can fall in love...
讓我們在愛河裡徜徉…
If you want to marry me, I will marry you.
如果你要娶我 我就嫁給你
That is good because I already made the down payment.
太好了 我已經付過首付了
I saved all my money and I bought this for you.
我用我所有的錢為你買下它
Get me Elliot Pellman.
幫我接接艾略特·帕爾曼
I have Chris Jones for you.
克裡斯·鐘斯讓我叫你
I'm just looking at it.
我正在看
Anything to be concerned about?
有什麼需要關注的嗎？
This Omalu, he's a coroner in Pittsburgh.
這個奧瑪魯是匹茲堡的一個驗屍官
He looks like a nobody, but... let me get into it.
看起來是個無名小卒 但是… 讓我調查一下
- Hello? - Is Bennet Omalu there?
- 你好 - 是班尼特·奧奧馬魯家嗎？
Ah, yes, he is.
呃 是的
Okay, yes?
嗯 你是？
I'm a neurologist who's worked around football for years.
我是一個做橄欖球相關研究很多年的神經學家
Very familiar with the NFL's concussion research.
對美國職業橄欖球聯盟的腦震盪研究非常瞭解
And the League concluded unequivocally that
聯盟的明確結論是
football players do not get brain damage.
橄欖球球員並不會得腦損傷
Webster was one random case, Mr.Omalu.
韋伯斯特是個偶然事件 奧瑪魯先生
- Doctor Omalu. - Well, whatever.
- 是奧奧馬魯醫生 - 隨你
You're an uneducated quack and your career is over.
你是一個無知的庸醫 你的職業生涯就要結束了
They said you were uneducated? Did they even read your resume?
他們說你是文盲嗎？他們沒有看過你的簡歷嗎？
Well I got calls too.
好吧 我也有電話
Apparently the National Football League owns neuroscience.
顯然美國國家橄欖球聯盟擁有自己的神經科學醫生
- Who knew? - Failure to find
- 是誰？- 沒找到
absence of clinical information.
臨床資訊的缺乏
- What do they want? - Your head on a spike.
- 他們想怎樣？- 懲罰你
- They want you to retract your findings. - They want you to say you made it all up.
- 他們希望你收回你的言論 - 他們想要你說你虛構了這一切
- I made it up? - They're accusing you of fraud.
- 我虛構的嗎？- 他們要指控你有欺詐行為
If you retract, you'll be fine.
如果你收回言論 你會沒事的
This all goes away.
這一切也就沒有意義了
- Why are they doing this? - They're terrified of you.
- 他們為什麼這麼做？- 他們害怕你
What'd you think they were gonna say? "Thank you"?
你以為他們會說什麼？"謝謝"？
- Yes. - What the hell for?
- 是的 - 為什麼？
For being told. For knowing.
為了知情權 為了真理
I understand. You think you're being a good American.
我明白 你覺得你在做好一個美國公民
So... the city of Pittsburgh spent $233 million
呃… 匹茲堡城市花了2.33億美元
to build their glorious Steelers a new stadium.
建造了他們的引以為傲的新鋼人體育場
All the while they were closing schools,
他們關閉學校
and raising taxes.
提高稅收
These people are not out to change the world.
這些人並不是要改變世界
And this is not some quaint academic discovery
這也不是附在一本名不見經傳的醫學期刊
stuck in the back of an obscure medical journal.
後面的奇怪的學術發現
Bennet Omalu is going to war with a corporation
班尼特·奧奧馬魯是要與一個集團展開一場鬥爭
That has 20 million people on a weekly basis
他們每週有20萬人
craving their product.
在期待著他們的比賽
The same way they crave food.
像期待將要上桌的飯菜
The NFL owns a day of the week.
美國職業橄欖球聯盟佔據著一周中的一天
The same day the church used to own, now it's theirs.
就像以前的教堂一樣 不過現在橄欖球是人們的信仰
They're very big.
他們很強大
Terry Long.
特裡·隆
His tests came back positive.
他的測試結果呈陽性
Football gave him CTE, and CTE told his brain
橄欖球造成了腦震盪 腦震盪損傷了大腦
to drink a gallon of antifreeze and he died.
他喝了一桶防凍液就自殺了
I told you there would be more.
我說過會有更多人
You have done great work.
你已經做了很偉大的工作
No one would blame you if you stopped now.
你就算現在放棄也沒人會怪你的
No one is stopping anything.
沒人會放棄的
Then I'd be lying if I didn't tell you
可能我不說的話就是自欺欺人了
how important your next move is.
你接下來做的事情非常重要
By the time Terry Long committed suicide,
特裡·隆自殺的時候
his brain had been consumed by Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy.
他的大腦早已經得了慢性創傷腦部病變
And it is probable, perhaps even likely,
甚至有可能
that a large percentage of professional football players,
大部分的職業球員
have and will die from CTE.
都會死於慢性創傷腦部病變
This was the Pittsburgh medical examiner's own, Dr.Bennet Omalu.
這是匹茲堡的法醫 班尼特·奧奧馬魯醫生
Who today threw down the gauntlet at the feet of the National Football League.
今天發起了對美國國家橄欖球聯盟的挑戰
Thank you.
謝謝
- What do you think? - I think you're gonna be an American hero.
- 你覺得怎麼樣？- 我想你會成為一個美國英雄的
- I'm not even an American. - Ah, that's even better.
- 我甚至不是一個土生土長的美國人 - 呃 那樣更好
That's so fucking American
去他娘的美國人
Doctor Maroon,
馬路恩醫生
who is also vice chairman of the neuro-surgery department
神經學會副主席
At the University of Pittsburghin Medical Centre ,
就職于匹茲堡大學醫學中心
said of Omalu's CTE diagnosis:
聲稱奧瑪魯的腦部慢性病變診斷
That it was fallacious reasoning.
荒謬至極
- Yes. - Is this Bennet Omalu?
- 你好 - 是班尼特·奧奧馬魯嗎？
Doctor Bennet Omalu.
是班尼特·奧奧馬魯醫生
You want to pussify this country?
你他媽想搞亂這個國家？
You want to vaginise football? Get the hell out, or they'll be doing your autopsy.
你他媽要搞死橄欖球嗎？滾遠點 否則被解剖的就是你
- Dr.Omalu? - Yes?.
- 奧瑪魯醫生？- 怎麼了？
I took you to be an early riser, I didn't want to call you at your office.
我猜你是個早起的人 我不想打到你辦公室
- This is Julian Bailes, do you know who I am? - I know who you are.
- 我是是朱利安·貝爾斯 你認識我嗎？- 認識
Mike Webster was a personal friend.
邁克·韋伯斯特曾經是我的好朋友
Was he?
是嗎？
Dr.Omalu, you're in trouble but you're not wrong.
奧瑪魯醫生 你雖然有麻煩但是你並沒有做錯
I would like to talk with you.
我想和你談談
The NFL has known about this concussion crisis for years.
國家橄欖球聯盟多年來一直知道腦震盪對人的影響
What you have there is the research,
這些是調查報告
that forms the basis for the league's concussion guidelines.
是聯盟對腦震盪調查方向的指南
In this study, some academics put helmets on monkeys,
在研究的時候 一些專家給猴子戴上頭盔
And shook them real hard, they threw dogs and pigs...
去進行猛烈地撞擊 還有狗和豬…
and human cadavers down elevator shafts.
還有人類屍體的升降落體實驗
Helmets on crash test dummies and bashed them together.
實驗人體和頭盔在一起碰撞形成衝擊
And their conclusion?
他們的結論是？
"No striking player experienced neck injury or concussion."
沒球員有明顯的頸部受傷或腦震盪
So a concussion is no more dangerous than a hangnail.
所以腦震盪甚至沒有手指頭的倒拉刺危險
- And that was it? - Oh, no, no, no.
- 就那樣了？- 哦 不不不
The NFL did what every organization does.
NFL作為一個聯盟
They put together a commission to study the study: "Dr.Elliot Pellman's
他們組成了一個委員會由艾略特醫生帶頭的
Mild Traumatic Brain committee".
"輕度腦創傷性委員會"
You know who else was on that committee?
你知道還有誰在這個委員會嗎？
Dr.Moroon Joe.
魔力紅醫生
Yeah, he was on there, plus a couple of others.
是的 有他 當然還有其它人
Team doctors, an equipment manager and two trainers.
醫生團隊 一個經理 兩個教練
Guys who tape knees for a living, I mean
我意思是大家其實都很難做
Why am I here, Dr.Bailes?
請我來這幹什麼 貝爾斯醫生？
Doctor, I'm not with the Steelers anymore.
醫生 我跟鋼人隊沒有一點關係了
I'm not with the NFL.
我也不在國家橄欖球聯盟工作
Now... Do you know how many Pittsburgh Steelers,
現在… 你知道有多少個鋼人隊的球員
just Steelers now, have died in the last few years?
只是鋼人隊 在過去的幾年裡死了的？
And I'm not talking about the older guys, I'm talking about men that I worked with.
我們不討論更早期的了 只討論一下我這一撥的
And just the ones I know about.
就我知道的
Twelve.
有12個
And I don't wanna see any more of these men vanish
我不想看到越來越多的人
in the back of a pickup truck.
重蹈賈斯汀的覆轍而消失
I know them, I was them.
我瞭解他們 我跟他們一樣
And I think you're doing this wrong.
我認為你這樣做是錯誤的
As long as the NFL continues to deny the truth,
只要國家橄欖球聯盟繼續否認事實
nothing changes.
什麼都不會改變
It's only true if they say it's true.
他們說是真的才是真的
And they gotta say it out loud.
他們還得公開地承認這一點
Get me a meeting with the commissioner.
讓我和委員們見一面
I want to sit with him man to man, face to face. I will make him say it out loud
我要這這些人面對面 我要讓他們大聲說出真相
They don't wanna talk to you.
他們不想和你見面
Football does not want to talk to you.
橄欖球不想跟你妥協
Like my daddy, a Louisiana Judge always used to say to me: "Son,
我的父親 路易斯安那的法官 他總是對我說
God is number one, and football is number two".
上帝排第一位 橄欖球排在第二位
Besides to them, you're not even American, You're not even African American.
而且 你還不是是美國人 甚至不是非裔美國人
You're...
你…
A doctor?
只是個醫生？
Okay.
好吧
Look... the league has kept everyone in the dark.
聯盟一直將真相隱藏在黑暗中
And you turned on the lights and gave
現在你打開了聚光燈
their biggest Boogeyman a name.
說出了他們的秘密
What's happening now?
現在是什麼狀況？
What you think they're doing to you? That's nothing.
你覺得他們會對你做什麼嗎？沒什麼
I've done my own research, on this "NFL Brain Injury Committee".
我已經調查了這個"國家橄欖球聯盟腦損傷研究小組"
You know what Dr.Elliot Pellman is? He's a rheumatologist.
你知道艾略特·佩爾曼醫生時幹什麼的嗎？他是一個風濕病學家
He's a specialist in arthritis and joint pain.
他的專業是關節炎和關節疼痛
Can you tell me, what a rheumatologist knows
你能告訴我風濕病學家知道什麼
about the brain and brain disease?
關於大腦和大腦疾病的東西？
Corporate men like this, in this country, usually go to Harvard or Yale.
在這個國家 這樣的人通常應該去哈佛或耶魯
He went to medical school in Guadalajara.
他去了在瓜達拉哈拉的醫學院
- Mexico? - Yes.
- 墨西哥的？- 是的
I did not know that.
我不知道
That's beautiful.
那很美
Now, two cases does not meet the scientific burden of proof.
現在 有兩個案例不滿足科學的舉證責任
You have to keep going.
你必須堅持住
Just so you understand, this does not show up on a CT scan.
正如你發現的 問題並不能在CT影像上呈現
Which means there is no diagnosis before death.
這就意味著死之前沒法診斷出來
In order for me to keep going...
我要堅持下去的話…
more have to die.
得有更多人死去
Unfortunately, that's already happening.
不幸的是 這已經發生了
Double D. Did I hear right we're losing you?
我沒聽錯吧？聽說你要走了？
Tapping you for mayor of Chicago?
去芝加哥做市長？
Still a long, long road, my friend.
還差很遠呢
All world killer athlete to civilian to king...
世界殺手級運動員 在一生中
all in one lifetime, ladies and gentlemen...
從平民到國王 女士們先生們…
I give you Mayor Dave Duerson, who has figured it out
能搞定一切的戴夫·杜爾森當選市長
- Dave - Yeah?
- 戴夫 - 有事嗎？
It's me man. Andre Waters.
是我 安德魯·瓦特斯
How're you doing, man?
你最近怎麼樣？
Look, let me walk with you.
我跟你走走吧
It's not good, Dave, not good.
不好 戴夫 很不好
You've seen the paperwork, why's the committee doing this, man?
你看過檔了吧 委員會怎麼能這麼做？
There are 5 other trustees, you talk to them?
還有5個其他受託人 你和他們談了嗎？
You the only one who played, man, You the only one who knows what it is to be us.
你是唯一和我們接觸的人 你是唯一瞭解我們的人
Hey, hey, hey, hey. You and me, we were the same man.
喂 喂 喂 喂 你和我 我們是一類的人
Huh? We were bangers, hitmen.
我們是炸彈 是殺手
File the appeal
拿檔去上訴
You denied the appeal, Dave Look, somethings wrong with me man.
你駁回了上訴 戴夫 你看 我們這些人身上是有問題的
I can't sleep, I mean my eyes get crossed It wears me out... Hey.
我睡不著 我是說我眼睛合上了又被弄開… 喂
- Look at me man. - Jesus!
- 看著我 - 我的天
Twelve years I payed my dues. I made millions for those assholes.
我交了十二年的稅 幫那些混蛋賺了幾百萬
Come on, just lend me your money, man.
拜託 借我點錢吧 夥計
Just asking back what I gave.
就當做還我一個人情了
Listen, FAT, stop eating like a pig. Got a headache? See a doctor.
聽著 肥豬 別像個豬一樣不停地吃了 頭痛嗎？去找醫生
I've seen 20 doctors. I just need rent money.
我已經看了20個醫生了 我需要借點錢
Get your shit together.
滾遠點
You used to be a warrior.
你曾是個勇士
- You fucking sellout. - Get your hands off me.
- 你這個叛徒 - 把你的手拿開
I'm Sorry, Dave, I'm sorry.
對不起 戴夫 對不起
Look, Hey, Hey, Remember when we were kids?
還記得我們小時候嗎？
Playing's what we live for, huh?
我們一起生活一起玩耍
I need your help...
我需要你的説明…
Dave, help me
戴夫 救救我
"Andre Waters, known as "Dirty Water", notorious for his aggressive style of play,
安德魯·瓦特斯 綽號"髒水" 他的進攻風格粗暴醜陋
and devastating hits that filled highlight reels.
最有名的是他具有毀滅性的兇猛擒抱
Waters died of a self-inflicted gunshot wound to the head.
瓦特斯吞槍自殺
He was 44.
終年44歲
And uh, this is the part where he uh...
呃 這只是一部分
He got knocked out.
他犯滿離場
He said he was alright.
他說自己沒事
He was maybe just a little dazed, but he said he was alright.
他也許只是有點眩暈 但他說自己沒問題
You look well.
你看起來氣色不錯
- How are the kids? - Kids are fine.
- 孩子們怎麼樣？-孩子們很好
I'm fine.
我也很好
I'm sorry I couldn't make it to the funeral.
對不起 我沒能參加他的葬禮
No one made it to the funeral.
沒人必須去參加的
He was the sun, we was the planets.
他是太陽 我們是行星
And then, after he give me this card he said: "Mom...
然後 他給我這張卡片後說:"媽媽…
I'm ready to go. "
我要走了
Because he knew that people was thinking he was crazy.
因為他知道人們都認為他瘋了
Not crazy, he had already become someone else.
他沒瘋 他只不過變成其它人了
You definitely think he had this disease? Because I want to believe that.
你真的認為他是得了這種病嗎？我希望是這樣
I believe so, yes.
我相信是這樣的
And now you want what's left of my boy.
你還想知道我的孩子留下了什麼
You heard about Mike Webster?
你知道邁克·韋伯斯特嗎？
And Terry Long and... and who else?
還有特裡·隆 還有… 還有其他人嗎？
What do you really want to ask me, Julian?
你到底想問我什麼 朱利安？
Dr.Cyril Wecht, Dr.Julian Bailes.
西瑞爾·威切特醫生 朱利安·貝爾斯醫生
Pleasure to meet you.
很高興見到你
Andre Waters.
安德魯·瓦特斯
Justin Strzelczyk.
賈斯汀·斯托克斯
And I just kept sending them back out there.
我只是不停地送走他們
What the hell were you thinking?
你到底在想些什麼？
You gotta be a part of it, you gotta be...
你必須和他們在一起 你應該…
On the sidelines with them to understand.
得站在他們的角度去理解問題
Whatever it takes to keep them in the game, To keep the whole thing going.
無論它們在比賽中的表現怎麼樣 都得堅持下去
Tape, Needles, Vicodin, Toradol, Lidocaine, Percocet,
膠帶 針頭 維柯丁 酮咯酸 利多卡因 撲熱息痛
Lexapro, Zoloft.
依地普林 郁樂複
Have I left anything out?
我有漏了說什麼嗎？
It's Tyres and oil.
這些就像是輪胎和汽油
It's mechanics trying to keep the cars on the racetrack.
是讓汽車在賽道上賓士的動力保障
Yeah, well, it's not medicine... I don't know what it is.
好吧 不是醫學… 我不知道是什麼
It's business.
是生意
- Oh, There you go. - Okay, Okay.
- 隨你便了 - 好了 好了
Three cases, is the scientific burden of evidence.
3個案例 才能支撐科學證據
We have 4. That is far beyond anything.
我們有4個 這比任何事情都重要
The NFL can or cannot deny.
不管國家橄欖球聯盟承認與否
This is bigger than they are.
這都比他們更厲害
They have to listen to us now.
他們現在應該聽我們的
Dr.Moroon, would you like a drink?
魔力紅醫生 你想喝點什麼？
- I said 5 minutes. - He doesn't want a drink.
- 我說了只有5分鐘時間 - 他不想喝東西
Your conclusions totally misrepresent the facts.
你的結論完全是在歪曲事實
To say that Webster, Long and Waters were killed by football is just...
所謂的韋伯斯特 隆 和瓦特斯是被橄欖球殺死的全都是…
Fallacious reasoning. Yes, I know.
錯誤的推理 是的 我知道
Where is he going with this?
他這是要幹嘛？
Just hear him out.
聽他說完
I would like to propose a formal, controlled study of former and current...
我想發起一個正式的 可控制的對於國家橄欖球聯盟
NFL football players.
現役和前成員的研究
We will bring together the greatest minds in America
讓我們一起給這個國家帶來偉大的思想
To solve the problem. We should be working together.
我們應該一起努力去解決這個問題
Who do you think you're talking to?
你以為你在跟誰說話？
Excuse me?
什麼意思？
I was the president of the congress of neurological surgeons.
我以前是神經外科醫協會的主席
And I was the man who performed the autopsies, on Mike Webster
我是給邁克·韋伯斯特做屍檢的人
Terry Long, your men.
特裡·隆 你的人
Men under your care.
歸你照看的人
Do you know what Mike Webster's wife said?
你知道邁克·韋伯斯特的妻子說了什麼嗎？
She said, that if she had known that Mike was sick,
她說 如果她知道邁克有病的話
She would have done more for him.
她該為他做更多的
But he died. In disgrace.
但是他死了 周圍的人都討厭他
Your man.
你的人
You took an oath.
你發過誓的
- Tell the truth. - The truth?
- 說出真相 - 真相？
Tell the truth.
把真相說出來吧
The truth is that the NFL is a blessing and a salvation, my friend.
真相就是美國橄欖球聯盟是崇高的 朋友
We employ hundreds of thousands of people.
我們提供成千上萬的崗位
We send thousands and thousands of poor kids, to school.
我們幫助成千上萬的貧困孩子走進學校
The ownership of this football club has donated millions of dollars
這些橄欖球俱樂部拿出成千上萬的美元
to countless charities.
成立慈善機構
Do you want me to go on?
你想讓我繼續講下去嗎？
- That won't be necessary. - Oh, it is necessary.
- 那都不重要 - 很重要
Football is the most popular sport in America.
橄欖球是美國最流行的運動
Because it is so god damn fantastic.
因為這項運動太他媽的不可思議了
And that, right there...
還有 就在那兒…
That is the beating heart of this city.
那兒就是這個城市的心臟
And you want to what? end it?
而你想幹什麼？消滅它？
You want to fold up the National Football League?
你想搞垮全國橄欖球聯賽？
I want to solve the problem.
我想解決問題
Who are you?
你憑什麼？
- What are you asking? - You're a pathologist, you perform autopsies.
- 你這是什麼意思？- 你是一個病理學家 驗屍官
Yes, I am a mere pathologist. That's it, that's all I am.
對 我是個驗屍官 是的 這就是我
- Do you have any idea the impact of what you're doing? - Yes, I do.
- 你知道你正在做的事會造成什麼影響嗎？- 當然 我知道
Do you understand the impact of what you are doing?
你知道你正在做的事會造成什麼影響嗎？
If just 10% of the mothers in America decide that
如果有10%的美國母親認為
football is too dangerous for their son's to play...
橄欖球太過危險而不讓孩子們去玩…
That is it. It is the end of football.
這樣的話 橄欖球完蛋了
Kids, Colleges and eventually it's just a matter of time, The professional game.
孩子們 學校和職業體育完蛋只是時間問題了
Joe, he does autopsies. He's not in the outcome business.
喬 他做屍體解剖 他不分析商業結果
He has no business.
他不考慮商業
Do you know what history does to people?
你知道歷史對人的影響嗎？
Trained physicians who ignore science...
那些訓練有素的醫生忽視科學…
- Oh, wow... - Sir, I am not done.
- 哦 哇… - 先生 我不會逃避
History laughs.
歷史的笑料
If you continue to deny my work, the world will deny my work.
如果你繼續否認我的工作 世界將會否認我的工作
But men, your men...
但是人 你的人
continue to die. Their families left in ruins.
會繼續死去 家庭因而破碎
Tell the truth.
把真相說出來
說出來
You sure, You sure you want to do this?
你確定 你確定想要這麼做？
I would ask you that same question, Dr.Moroon.
同樣的問題我問問你 魔力紅醫生
Oh, your study. I'll get back to you.
嗯 你的研究 我會回復你
Well, that went well.
好吧 一切順利
When I was a boy, growing up in Nigeria...
當我還是個孩子的時候 在奈及利亞長大…
Heaven was here...
天堂在這裡…
and America was here.
而美國就在這裡
To me it was the place where God sent all of his favorite people.
對我來說天堂就是上帝把所有他喜歡的人召集在一起的地方
You could be anything, you could do anything.
你可以想任何事 你可以做任何事
Americans were the manifestation of what God wanted us all to be.
我以為上帝喜歡的大概就是美國人那樣的人
I have never wanted anything...
我從來沒有這麼想…
as much as I wanted to be accepted as an American.
成為一個為人所接受的美國人
But Mike Webster goes mad, and nobody asks why.
但是邁克·韋伯斯特瘋的時候竟然沒有人去問為什麼
They make fun of him, they insult him on TV.
他們嘲笑他 在電視上侮辱他
And now they want to pretend that his disease does not exist.
而現在他們又想要假裝他的病是不存在的
And they want to bury me.
他們還想掩蓋我的發現
It's offensive.
這是攻擊
I am offended
我是靶子
I am the wrong person to have discovered this.
我不應該發現這個
There is no coincidence in this world.
這世界上沒有巧合
Tell me, what is the statistical probability that you?
告訴我 你 不僅僅作為一個醫生
Not just a doctor, but Bennet Omalu...
還是班尼特·奧奧馬魯 來到美國
came to America, ended up here,
紮根在這裡 在這個腐朽的地方
This rusty place, for you alone to be the one to see this?
你一個人看著這一切的概率是多大？
When I arrived in New York...
當我抵達紐約的時候…
- I was attacked. - What happened?
- 我遇到了襲擊 - 發生什麼事了？
Something that is better left unsaid.
還是不說比較好
But that man, almost broke me.
但那個人 快要把我打死了
I wanted to give up and go back.
我想要放棄了 想回去
But I knew God.
但是我相信上帝
I decided to trust his wisdom.
我相信上帝的聖明
And I stayed.
我留下了
And now I am looking at this man... An Omalu Onyemalukwubwe.
而現在我眼前的這個人… 奧瑪魯·杌隉瑪魯庫伯
your name, it means "If you know...
你的名字 意味著"如果你知道…
You must come forth and speak".
你必須站出來公之於眾"
- How did you know that? - I called your father.
- 你是怎麼知道那個的？- 我打電話給你的父親了
- He was pleased to hear from me. - Yes. I am sure he was.
- 他聽到我說的話很高興 - 我相信他很高興
If you don't speak for the dead, who will?
假如你不把死因說出來 誰來說？
You are of the Igbo tribe, Bennet.
你是義博部落出生的人 班尼特
When you have the truth, the thing
當你知道了事情的真相 有被告知
you are told you cannot do is the thing you must do.
你不能做的事 那就是你要做的事
Embrace that, and nothing created by man can bring you down.
去吧 沒有人能夠打倒你
Omalu's gone to the press now, listen to this.
奧奧馬魯去出版社了 聽這個
"After examining the remains of former National Football League player Andre Waters,
在國家橄欖球運動員安德魯·瓦特斯的遺體解剖結束後
a neuropathologist in Pittsburgh, Dr.Bennet Omalu is claiming...
在匹茲堡的驗屍官班尼特·奧奧馬魯醫生聲稱…
That Mr.Waters had sustained brain damage from playing football, and he says...
瓦特斯先生在職業生涯期間受到了持續的腦損傷…
that led to his depression and ultimate death.
最終導致了他的抑鬱和死亡
It gets worse.
越來越糟糕
Dr.Julian Bailes, Medical Director for the Centre for the Study of Retired Athletes,
朱利安·貝爾斯醫生 退役運動員研究中心主任
and the Chairman of the Department of Neurosurgery...
西維吉尼亞大學的
of West Virginia University said:
神經外科學系的主席 表示：
"Unfortunately, I'm not shocked."
"很遺憾 我並不感到驚訝"
There's more Omalu and more Bailes.
會有更多的奧瑪魯和貝爾斯出現的
Bailes. Why do I know that name?
貝爾斯 這個名字怎麼有點耳熟？
Steeler's Team Doctor, Neurologist for the Players Association.
鋼人隊的團隊醫生 球員協會的神經學專家
- Wow... - Yeah, Wow.
- 哇… - 是的 哇
The Times is calling it a potential epidemic.
《紐約時報》稱這是潛在的瘟疫
Paul... It's not the sports section, not science.
保羅… 這不是什麼體育專欄 不是科學期刊
It's A1, front page, New York Times.
在紐約時報的首頁 頭條
Apparently, the commissioner has been yearning for years...
顯然 總裁多年來一直渴望…
to go back to his litigator... since Paul Tagliabue announced that he would retire...
根據律師的回饋… 保羅·塔利亞布埃宣佈他將退役…
in July, after nearly 17 years...
在七月 差不多17年後…
Prized, The most lucrative and stabilizing reign, perhaps in the history.
國家橄欖球聯盟 也許是史上最有價值最穩定最賺錢的體育聯盟
Football at the NFL owners meeting in O'Doherty...
在奧多爾蒂國家橄欖球聯盟俱樂部經理會議上…
There's a new sheriff in town. His name is Roger Goodell.
一個新總裁出現了 他的名字叫羅傑·古德爾
What I'm here to do now is protect the shield.
現在讓我來為這個聯盟說句話
The NFL isn't just a sports league.
國家橄欖球聯盟不僅僅是一個體育聯賽
It's an entertainment product.
它也是一個娛樂產品
America's Game.
是美國人的遊戲
I want us to go on enjoying...
我希望我們能繼續享受它給我們帶來的樂趣…
Allegheny County Coroner...
阿勒格尼縣驗屍中心…
Sure, one second.
好的 稍等
It's Dr.Julian Bailes.
朱利安·貝爾斯醫生
- Yes, yeah. - Here he is.
- 好的 - 他來了
- Julian - Hey, Turn on the TV.
- 朱利安 - 嗯 打開電視機
Yes, I'm watching.
嗯 我在看了
You asked for a face to face with the Commissioner... Man to Man?
你想要的和委員面對面的？
Goodell and the NFL are asking for a concussion summit.
古德爾邀請你出席國家橄欖球聯賽的腦震盪研究會議
A full presentation in Chicago next week.
下周在芝加哥進行一個完整的演示
They heard you, you have your shot.
他們知道你了 該你出手了
Julian...
朱利安…
Why don't you throw in some football stuff?
你為什麼不加入一些有關橄欖球的材料？
Some non-medical terms, things we'd say.
我們需要說的東西 一些非醫學術語
Why do I need to say things they'd say?
我們為什麼要說他們要說的是東西？
I thought I was here for the other reason.
我還以為以為我在這裡是為了別的原因
You have what? 7 or 8 degrees? you're one of the smartest people they'll ever meet...
你有什麼？7個甚至8個學歷？你將是他們見過的最聰明的人之一
You know what? You're gonna be fine...
你知道嗎？你會成功的…
How about you?
你沒事吧？
How will you be?
你會怎麼樣？
You know, it is a mindless, violent game.
你知道 這是一個愚蠢又暴力的遊戲
And then it's Shakespeare.
很莎士比亞
I mean to me, it's like life that way.
我的意思是對我而言 就像生活一樣
And I know you can't see how...
我知道你不明白…
exciting, and beautiful all that is, and I don't blame you.
那是多麼的刺激多麼的競猜 我不會怪你
But what I'm trying to tell you is... This is not fun for me.
但我要告訴你的是… 這對我來說一點也不好玩
All of the people we're gonna see tomorrow, I know them personally.
明天我們看到的所有人 私底下我都認識
And that feeling you have when someone you love and admire,
你對於那些你喜歡和尊敬的人讓你滾蛋
screws you over...
所產生的一切感覺…
They're gonna have that feeling...
他們會有的就是那種感覺…
Because of me.
因為我
And there's not a damn thing I can do about it.
我卻什麼都做不到
- Hey - We have to talk.
- 嘿 - 我們必須談談
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
There is no easy way to say this, so I'm just going to say it.
沒法委婉地說 我就直說了
They're not going to let you speak.
他們不想讓你說話
What?
什麼？
They don't even want you in the room.
他們甚至不希望你在會場
They want me to do it.
他們想讓我去做
- One of their own. - One of their own.
- 一個他們自己的人 - 一個他們自己的人
- So they want to pretend... - that you don't even exist, that's right...
- 所以他們想假裝… - 假裝你不存在 是的…
- They still have to sit and listen. - To you
- 他們還得坐下來聽 - 你
- Yes, you blew up their whole world. - And yours, Julian.
- 是的 你毀了他們的世界 - 還有你的 朱利安
Yes, mine.
是的 還有我的
Because how can it be possible, that some African Voodoo Doctor
因為覺得一個非洲巫術醫生怎麼可能
could understand this subject better than them.
會比他們更深入地瞭解這個問題
Or even better than you
甚至比你還瞭解
Wait a second, you think this is about Bennet Omalu?
等一會兒 你覺得這是針對班尼特·奧奧馬魯嗎？
I'm not here because of you, I'm here because people are dying.
我會在這裡不是因為你 而是因為有人在死去
You are here for redemption. You are here to use me to cleanse your sins.
你在這裡是為了贖罪 你在這裡是想用我去洗刷你的罪惡
You self-righteous bastard.
你這個自以為是的混蛋
Do you have any idea what I could have? How much I could have?
你知道如果站到聯盟那邊一直守口如瓶
If I went back to my side of the ball and just kept my mouth shut.
我能得到什麼嗎？知道我能得到多少嗎？
Everything in my world is telling me not to agree with you,
我世界中的一切事物都在阻止我同意你
except one.
只有一個例外
Science.
科學
So, here I am.
這才是我在這兒的理由
Up here beside you, not down there in that audience with them.
站在你旁邊 而不是和他們坐在觀眾席
What more can I do to prove myself to you?
還需要我做什麼向你證明嗎？
I am sorry.
我很抱歉
Convince them, Julian.
說服他們 朱利安
You know, my father can't remember a god damn thing
我父親記不住這該死的事
He never played a day of football.
他從沒打過一天橄欖球
He was too busy working in a factory, you quack.
他忙著在工廠工作 你這個庸醫
I beg your pardon?
再說一遍？
You take your bullshit science and go back to Africa.
帶著你的狗屎科學滾回非洲去吧
And get away from our game.
離我們的遊戲遠點
What happened?
怎麼了？
Roger Goodell just said that Justin Strzelczyk
羅傑·古德爾只是說了賈斯汀·斯托克斯
May have got his concussion swimming.
可能是游泳時候造成的腦震盪
- In a swimming pool. - That, That's insanity.
- 在一個游泳池 - 完全是胡說
This whole thing was staged.
先不說這個
They needed to say they heard us so they could god damn bury us.
他們需要說他們聽了我們的了 那麼他們才能埋沒我們
The science means nothing to them.
科學對他們來說毫無意義
This is an important day, in the National Football League...
對國家橄欖球聯盟來說今天是個重要的日子…
We've had some very good dialogue,
我們收到了很多重要的意見
Which will help us improve the care for our players.
這將幫助我們進一步照顧我們的球員
What do you think when you hear about former NFL players suffering from symptoms that
當你聽到很多退役球員患有
has only been seen in boxers and people that are over 80 years old?
只有拳擊手和80歲以上的人才有的病症時怎麼想？
I mean what does that say about the effects of concussions on players?
我的意思是說腦震盪對球員的影響有什麼想說的？
I'm not a doctor here, but you have to look at their entire medical history.
我不是醫生 但是你看看整個醫學發展史
This is an evolving science, and that's okay.
這是一項不斷發展的科學 就是這樣
While I agree with the commissioner, no empirically determined proof was presented today,
我同意委員的看法 今天並沒有提出關鍵性的證據
because there simply isn't any.
因為根本就沒有
Because according to the NFL's own numbers
因為根據國家橄欖球聯盟的資料統計
half of all players with concussions are sent back into the same game.
超過一半的得過腦震盪的球員最後都回到比賽中去了
Including some who were actually knocked out cold.
包括一些曾被撞暈過的人
Ira Casson, was head of a team of NFL doctors
艾勒·卡森 曾是國際橄欖球聯盟的團隊主管醫生
who had looked into the issue,
他看到這個問題以後
and determined that the concern over head injuries was overblown.
認為頭部受傷的擔憂顯然被誇大了
Is there any evidence, as far as you're concerned...
從您的觀點來說 有沒有什麼和…
that links multiple head injuries
出現在職業橄欖球運動員裡
among pro football players with... depression?
多人顱腦損傷… 抑鬱症相關聯的證據？
No.
沒有
- With Dementia? - No.
- 老年癡呆？- 沒有
- With early onset of Alzheimer's? - No.
- 伴隨早期老年癡呆症發作？- 沒有
Is there any evidence as of today that links
沒有任何證據可以證明
Multiple head injuries with any long term problem like that?
多次頭部損傷會產生後遺症的問題？
- In NFL players? - Yeah.
- 在國家橄欖球聯盟球員中嗎？- 是的
No.
沒有
Hey little one.
嘿 小傢伙
This is your father.
我是你老爸
I am in deep shit.
我踩到狗屎了
I have not done anything wrong...
雖然我並沒有做錯什麼…
but I am being punished.
但是我被懲罰了
It might not be so nice, when you get out here
當你離開媽媽肚子的時候可能發現世界並不美好
You are still with God.
你現在和上帝在一起
Please ask him to help me.
請讓他幫幫我
It's alright, it's okay...
都過去了 沒關係…
- What is this? - This is the FBI.
- 什麼情況？- 他們來自FBI
Apparently I'm being relieved of my duties.
顯然我被解除責任了
What? I don't understand.
什麼？我不明白
Dr.Wecht has been indicted on 84 federal counts including...
威切特醫生被聯邦方面指控從1984年開始…
Please Tex, let me at least have the joy of telling him.
拜託 特克斯 至少讓我有告訴他這多麼有趣
I'm being indicted on 84 federal counts,
我被聯邦法院指控從84年開始
including mail fraud, wire fraud, other related offences.
進行郵件欺詐、通信欺詐、等相關罪行
Arising out of my use of government resources, to advance my private practice.
利用政府資源扶持我的私人診所
Including but not limited to:
包括但不限於:
Mileage vouchers, misuse of office stationary,
濫用交通補助和辦公用品
and my personal use of the fax machine.
還有違規使用傳真機
- Faxes? - Yeah.
- 傳真？- 是的
They could not have come up with something this stupid in Nigeria.
這些愚蠢的理由在奈及利亞都行不通
This man has been a public servant for decades.
這個人幾十年來一直為人民服務
Cyril.
西瑞爾
Have you ever performed any private services on county time?
你有沒有做過任何以公謀私的事情？
Have I?
我？
Apparently we've both hurt the government's feelings
顯然我們都傷害了政府的的感情
Are you referring to the death row case? Where I used my personal time.
你指的是死刑案件嗎？我都是用的業餘時間
We don't want you, Dr.Omalu. But we can have you.
我們不會為難你 奧瑪魯醫生 但是我們需要你
- And what does that mean? - That means they want your testimony.
- 這是什麼意思？- 意思是說他們需要你的證詞
- Against you? - Yes.
- 針對你？- 是的
I understand.
我明白了
You are attacking him, to get to me.
你們先攻擊他 然後就是我
I know.
我懂了
This is because his name is on my research.
這是因為他的名字在我的調查報告上
What research is that?
什麼調查？
I will resign first.
我會儘快辭職的
In which case your immigration status will be revised.
在這種情況下 你的移民身份將會發生變化
Since your status requires full-time employment.
因為你的身份需要全職工作
Then I will get another job in another city.
我會去別的城市再找一份工作的
- That would be fine.
那樣最好
Bennet...
班尼特…
All I asked, is that if you did this, we both came out okay.
我跟你說過 如果你要做 確保我們都能夠沒有麻煩
Not professional ruination.
而不是丟了工作
Whoever... Whatever takes over from me...
任何人… 不管誰取代我…
They're gonna want the CTE information, you know that.
他們都是為了腦損傷的資料
- What if they show up here with a warrant? - On suspicion of what? Science?
- 如果他們帶著正當理由出現在這裡呢？- 懷疑什麼？科學？
Ah, on suspicion of bullshit. We got screwed...
啊 因涉嫌胡說 我們受到了不公正的待遇…
You didn't deserve it.
這不是你該得到的結果
You know the worst part? How easy it was.
你知道最糟糕的是什麼嗎？太容易了
Cyril, they are not going to make me say...
西瑞爾 他們休想讓我說出
one word against you.
一個指控你的字
What are you gonna say?
你會說什麼？
"Cyril Wecht's a loud-mouthed asshole"?
"西瑞爾·威切特是個白癡"？
I don't care, I'm tired.
我不在乎 我累了
My balls are low.
我年紀大了
I didn't do good enough by you.
我沒有為做好什麼
Cyril... I can not go back to Nigeria.
西瑞爾… 我不能回到奈及利亞
Everything that I am is here.
我的一切都在這兒
My child has got to be born in America.
我的孩子要出生在美國
Don't worry, I'll get you a job.
別擔心 我會給你一份工作
You can work with me in the prison laundry.
你可以和我在監獄的洗衣房一起幹活
Call the surgeon. We need a god damned drink.
打電話外科醫生 我們需要喝幾杯
I solved the problem.
我把這個問題解決了
All the have to do is put on the side of the helmet,
所有要做的就是把安全帽放到一邊
"The Surgeon General has determined that playing football is hazardous to your health."
"普通外科醫生就會認定打球對你的健康是有害的"
You gotta put it on both sides of the helmet.
你必須把雙方的安全帽都拿掉
Did you know that Paul Tagliabue, this is the former commissioner Tagliabue...
你知不知道保羅·塔利亞布埃 聯盟前委員…
Did you know that Paul was a partner at Covington & Burling?
你知道科文頓柏靈律師事務所的合夥人保羅嗎？
which is the same law firm that represented the Big 7 Tobacco companies.
也就是7大煙草公司的事務所
- Course he was. - And now they're representing the National Football League.
- 當然 - 現在他們代言了國家橄欖球聯盟
Of course they do.
他們當然會這樣
In my last year with the Steelers,
我在鋼人隊的最後一年
We moved a game from a Sunday to a Tuesday because of a blizzard.
因為暴風雪 我們把比賽從周日改到了週二
And the league said that they weren't concerned about the ratings,
聯盟說不用擔心收視率
because the league was immune from acts of God.
因為聯盟是被神保佑的
Bennet! Bennet!
班尼特 班尼特
I'm so sorry, there's no heartbeat.
很抱歉 沒有心跳了
May, May we have the room?
能讓我們兩個人一起呆一會兒嗎？
Please, Excuse us, thank you.
拜託了 謝謝
I am so sorry.
我很抱歉
I am sorry that our baby's dead.
孩子沒了我很抱歉
This is my fault.
都是我的錯
I wish I'd never met Mike Webster.
真希望我從沒見過邁克·韋伯斯特
They destroyed us.
他們毀了我們
And I don't understand why it is happening this way.
我不明白事情為什麼會這樣
Bennet, listen to me.
班尼特 聽我說
Do you know what I chose to fake?
你知道我選擇的明燈是誰嗎？
You.
是你
- We will have this family. - Yes, we will.
- 我們會有個家的 - 嗯 我們會有的
Just not here.
但不是在這兒
We have to go.
我們得走了
Hello, Mr Omalu?
你好 奧瑪魯先生？
Doctor Omalu.
奧瑪魯醫生
I just need the measurements for the flat screens.
我們需要知道你的電視機尺寸
That won't be necessary.
沒必要了
加利福利亞 洛帝
三年後
Tell me what happened to you, Jose.
告訴我你怎麼了 約瑟
Tell me.
告訴我
It's going to be okay.
都會好的
My mind keeps slipping.
我的思維一直在弱化
I can't seem to find the damn words no more.
我甚至不回說話了
What?
什麼？
Yeah Yeah Yeah.
嗯 嗯 嗯
I just can't do this, I'm sorry.
我不行了 我很抱歉
- Yes? - Bennet it's Julian.
- 誰啊？- 是我朱利安
Dave Duerson killed himself today.
戴夫·杜爾森今天自殺了
He shot himself in the chest, in the heart.
他朝自己的胸部開了一槍
Hold on, Hold on.
等等 等等
- Oh My God. - He left a note.
- 我的天 - 他留下了一張字條
He wants his brain to be donated, to be examined.
他希望死後將大腦捐贈出去做研究
They said that we were right.
他認為我們是正確的
Bennet, are you there?
班尼特 你在嗎？
Yes, Yes, I'm here.
嗯 我在
A Pro-Bowler in that deep with NFL leadership, killing himself in the way he killed himself.
一個國家橄欖球聯盟專業的頂級的投球手 用自己的方式自殺了
They can't explain this one away.
他們解釋不了這個
Players are gonna want to hear from you now.
球員們現在想要聽見你的聲音
Trying to find the...
我想找那件…
I don't know what to say to them.
我不知道該對他們說什麼
Tell them what's really happening.
告訴他們到底發生了什麼
Hello.
大家好
A small boy came to me...
一個小男孩來找我…
and said, Mister, why do you hate football?
說:先生 為什麼你那麼討厭橄欖球？
I said I don't hate football.
我說我不討厭橄欖球啊
He said: "Yes, my father said you hate football."
他說："我爸爸說你討厭橄欖球"
I said, "You tell your father to come see me."
我說"你告訴你父親來見我"
My wife watches the games.
我的妻子喜歡在看比賽
And she will scream and she will jump.
她會尖叫 甚至會跳起來
She startles me, a lot.
她總是嚇到我
But through her eyes I can see the beauty, and the grace...
但通過她的眼睛 我能看到美 看到優雅…
The power.
還有能量
I said to her that I wished I'd never met Mike Webster.
我告訴她 我寧願從沒見過邁克·韋伯斯特
But that was before I knew him.
但在我認識他之前
He has given me a great gift.
他給了我一個大禮物
A dangerous gift.
這禮物是危險的
The gift of knowing.
這禮物是知識
When a man is a soldier, he knows what is at risk.
一個士兵 知道什麼是危險
He may be injured or even killed.
可能會受傷 甚至死亡
But when a man is a football player,
但是作為一個職業球員
He knows he may break his arm, or his leg
知道自己可能會斷手 斷腿
He does not know that he can lose his mind.
他不知道還會失去自己的思想
His family, his money.
失去家庭和金錢
His life.
還有他的生活
They have to know.
他們應該知道
Mike Webster, Justin Strzelczyk
邁克·韋伯斯特 賈斯汀·斯托克斯
Terry Long, Andre Waters,
特裡·隆 安德魯·瓦特斯
Dave Duerson.
戴夫·杜爾森
By Dying...
他們通過死亡…
They speak for the living.
來為生存代言
And I speak for them.
而我為他們代言
That is all I do.
這就是我所做的
Forgive them.
原諒他們
Forgive Yourselves.
原諒自己
Be at peace.
淡然處之
Commissioner Goodell, is there a link between
古德爾總裁 你認為打職業橄欖球
playing professional football and the likelihood
和腦相關的損傷之間
of contracting a brain related injury,
有沒有什麼關聯
Such as dementia, Alzheimer's, depression, or CTE?
如癡呆 阿爾茨海默氏症 抑鬱症 或慢性腦損傷病變？
We are doing everything we possibly can for our players.
我們做了一切能為球員做的
I just asked you a simple question. What's the answer?
我只想問你一個簡單的問題 答案是什麼？
It sort of reminds me of the tobacco companies,
它讓我想起了煙草公司
Pre 90's, when they kept saying:
90年代以前 當他們不停地說:
"No, there is no link between smoking and damage to your health, or ill health effects."
"不 吸煙和健康問題 疾病因素沒有關聯性"
And they were forced to admit that that was incorrect through a spate of litigation in the 1990's..
通過在1990年代一連串的訴訟 最終他們被迫承認那是不對的
And my question to you is...
我要問你的是…
We have heard from the NFL time and time again.
我們一次又一次的從國家橄欖球聯盟聽到
You're always studying, you're always trying.
你一直努力 你一直嘗試
- You're hopeful... I wanna know, - Son of a bitch
- 你很有前途… 我想知道 - 雜種
What are you doing in the negotiations that are going on now
你在這次洽談裡都做了什麼
to deal with this problem and other problems related
來處理這個問題和其他關於橄欖球運動員所
to the injuries that football players obtain,
受到傷害的問題
and it's impact on their health?
以及這些問題對他們健康的影響？
You did all this.
你做的一切
I know my time is drawing to a close,
我知道時間不多了
but let me just say this to Mr.Goodell
但是讓我告訴古德爾先生
and everybody who is here today, that I think that it's time Congress...
以及今天在場的每一個人 我認為國會是時候…
- First time in Washington? - Ah, yes.
- 第一次來華盛頓嗎？- 啊 是的
Well, we're thrilled you accepted our invitation.
我們非常高興你能接受我們的邀請
I was very curious.
我很好奇
Chief Medical Examiner for Washington, DC
成為華盛頓特區首席法醫的話
means you would also consult with the CIA and FBI,
意味著你也得接受中央情報局和聯邦調查局的諮詢
and any foreign government requesting the assistance
還有任何外國政府對於
of the United States Government.
美國政府的援助請求
Essentially, you are America's forensic pathologist.
從本質上講 作為一名國家法醫病理學家
Wouldn't have to put on scrubs, perform an autopsy.
不需要像個實習醫生那樣進行屍檢
You're beyond all that now.
那些都不需要做了
Would you like to hear about the benefits package?
你想瞭解更多的相關福利嗎？
No, I mean, I'm sure it's fine.
不用了 我的意思是 肯定很好
We know everything you did, Dr.Omalu.
我們知道你所經歷的一切 奧奧馬魯醫生
You exemplify everything it is to be an American.
你例證了作為一個美國公民的一切意義
You belong here with us, in the nations capital.
你屬於這兒 在首都和我們一起工作
Why don't you take a couple of days and think about it?
何不休息兩天好好考慮一下？
Let's go
我們開始吧
You. On the ball
你 看球
Bring it back, huddle up
把它拿回來 彎腰
Get him, get him, get him
抓住他 抓住他 抓住他
奧奧馬魯醫生推辭了華盛頓的工作
他依然留在加利福利亞 洛迪
和普蕾瑪還有兩個孩子一起
Tragic loss for the family and fans of former Chargers star Junior Seau,
對前電光隊球星朱尼耶·薩烏的家人和球迷來說真是災難性的消息
after he was found dead in his ocean-side home.
他的屍體在海邊被發現
Good evening and thanks for joining us tonight.
晚上好 感謝您的收看
Junior Seau's death is being investigated as a suicide.
朱尼耶·薩烏的死亡正在調查中
Police say his girlfriend reported finding him
警方表明 他的女朋友報告說發現他
with an apparently self-inflicted gunshot wound to the chest...
朝自己的胸部開槍自殺身亡…
Tonight there's widespread shock and disbelief over the sudden death.
突然地離去消息讓大家震驚 難以置信
2011年 退役的國家橄欖球聯盟球員開始控訴聯盟
理由是聯盟隱藏震盪效應的危害
最終有超過5000起訴訟
國家橄欖球聯盟在不公開其何時知道震盪效應
對橄欖球運動員有什麼影響
的前提條件下解決了該問題
國家橄欖球聯盟雇傭的精算師
計算總結出28%的職業橄欖球運動員
會受到嚴重的認知損害 包括慢性腦部病變
聯邦對西瑞爾·威切特的所有指控
都被撤銷
2015年2月 班尼特·奧奧馬魯醫生成為
美利堅合眾國公民